<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Andrew's Book Reviews</title>
        <link>http://ndrewsemler.com/reviews</link>
        <description><![CDATA[This feed provides recent Book Reviews by Andrew]]></description>
        <atom:link href="http://ndrewsemler.com/reviews/review_rss.xml" rel="self"
                   type="application/rss+xml" />
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UT</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
    <title>Cat's Cradle - Kurt Vonnegut</title>
    <link>http://ndrewsemler.com/reviews/posts/2016-04-01-Cats_Cradle.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="info">
    Posted on April  1, 2016
    
        by Andrew 
        
    
</div>
<img src="../images/catscradle.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 10px; width:200px;" />
<p>The father of the atom bomb has left his own children a gift. Ice-nine is a dangerous substance. It’s capable of turning water to ice at room temperature. His three dysfunctional children split it. How will they handle the responsibility?</p>
<p>Cat’s Cradle is a Vonnegut novel. This means the novel is not about what it says on the cover. Vonnegut takes you on a stroll with words. Casually “spoiling” the novel at multiple points. Surprisingly the story is fairly linear. Less surprisingly the main character is an author writing a story about himself writing a novel.</p>
<p>The novel is also the author’s conversion story. It shows a philosophy of cheerfulness in the face of oblivion. The philosophy is made into a religion. Bokononism was outlawed by it’s own creators to give people more zest in their lives.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All of the true things that I am about to tell you are shameless lies.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Primarily of course, this novel is a comedy. It is best described as oblivious juxtaposition. At one point Angela is complaining about how little money her father made for making the atom bomb. Simultaneously her brother’s artwork is going to make a villager rich. It’s waterlogged crap.</p>
<p>If you were looking for a Kurt Vonnegut novel about human nature I’d recommend “God Bless You, Mr Rosewater”. For a sci-fi novel I’d recommend starting with “The Sirens of Titan”. That said you will still be laughing and engaging in an uncomfortable amount of self-reflection.</p>
<div> Rating:

    No rating given

</div>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://ndrewsemler.com/reviews/posts/2016-04-01-Cats_Cradle.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Andrew</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Traitor Baru Cormorant - Seth Dickinson</title>
    <link>http://ndrewsemler.com/reviews/posts/2016-03-30-The_Traitor_Baru_Comorant.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="info">
    Posted on March 30, 2016
    
        by Andrew 
        
    
</div>
<img src="../images/ttbc.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 10px; width:200px;" />
<p>I never knew accounting could feel this energising. This book is set in an alternate past where the Masquerade is an empire that is achieving conquest through economics rather than through the strength of their Navy or Calvary. Appropriately the main character(Baru) is a bright accountant. She is tasked with cruel task of controlling and conquering a country. Just as the Masquerade conquered hers. Will Baru be able to maintain her appearance as a loyalist?</p>
<p>I read this over the past two days when I should have been sleeping and found it about as stressful to read as Argo was to watch. Multiple crowning moments of awesome which were tempered by the disgust I felt throughout the whole novel.</p>
<p>If you have ever been annoyed when a main character fails to do the maths and make an emotionally hard choice this book will be for you. In many cases Baru makes choices much harder than you would reasonably expect even a competent hero to perform and moves into the realm of a monster.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“If the Masquerade could not be stopped by spear of treaty, she would change it from within”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have never felt more uncomfortable reading a novel but was still unable to put it down. The uncomfortableness is a direct result of the anti-imperialism themes throughout the book as the Masquerade seek to restrict personal choice everywhere they spread. It is everywhere you look in this novel.</p>
<p>You can read the start of the book from <a href="http://www.tor.com/2015/05/26/excerpt-the-traitor-baru-cormorant-seth-dickinson/">here</a></p>
<div> Rating:

    <img src="../images/thumbsup_s.png" height="26px">

</div>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://ndrewsemler.com/reviews/posts/2016-03-30-The_Traitor_Baru_Comorant.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Andrew</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Annihilation - Jeff VanderMeer</title>
    <link>http://ndrewsemler.com/reviews/posts/2016-03-30-Annihilation.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="info">
    Posted on March 30, 2016
    
        by Andrew 
        
            - edited by Emily
        
    
</div>
<img src="../images/annihilation.jpg" style="float: right; margin: 10px; width:200px;" />
<p>This is a seriously creepy sci-fi post apocalypse novel that follows a biologist on expedition into Area X. Her expedition runs into the tower. A mysterious living structure embedded into the ground. Who is producing the writing on the wall? Why does it seem alive?</p>
<p>I am not particularly familiar with Horror. I tend to find the genre hides information, in most cases, seemingly at random. It often is also filled with characters holding the idiot ball. Instead of scary this tends to make the genre irritating. I’m pleased to say Annihilation didn’t do that. The biologist picked up information and shared it with the reader. The biologist was also a biologist (i.e not a complete idiot). There was still a problem, though. The information she picked up didn’t really help her. In this, the novel perfectly captured the feeling of a false explanation.</p>
<p>The general creepy-ness factor of this goes up as the novel progresses. You learn that, unlike most post apocalypse stories, most people aren’t actually aware they’re in a post apocalypse world. A sense of inevitability follows; you know nothing good is going to happen but you’re not going to stop reading. I lent this book to a friend. They read it in a single weekend.</p>
<p>The speed at which I read this possibly caused me to miss a lot of the twists. Every one I came across felt non-obvious and out of the blue. The sinking feeling you get as you experience the horror is truly excellent. As is to be expected, parts of the ending were a little weird. The ending was strange in a different direction to the rest of the novel. Despite this, it was satisfying for several reasons. You arrived at the end not knowing too much so there was a feeling of anti-climax which fit with the feeling generated by the rest of the novel.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Can you really imagine what it was like in those first moments, peering down into that dark space, and <em>seeing that</em>? Perhaps you can. Perhaps you’re staring at it now”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is the first novel in a trilogy. Even though I loved the feeling as I read this novel I’m not certain I want to read the second. Mostly, this was due to arriving at the end with the amount of information you did. Not enough to ruin the ending but far too much to see where a sequel would go. The second novel is apparently set in a different part of the Annihilation Universe, which may be little enough of a sequel so as to be readable. Who knows.</p>
<p>I got a physical copy but there is also a kindle version which means you can find a small preview on Amazon</p>
<div> Rating:

    <img src="../images/thumbsup_s.png" height="26px">

</div>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://ndrewsemler.com/reviews/posts/2016-03-30-Annihilation.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Andrew</dc:creator>
</item>

    </channel>
</rss>
